>> Jem Young: 但是，一般来说，会有一堆服务器。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But, generally, there's
gonna be stacks and stacks of servers.
因此，如果您想将笔记本电脑或台式机或计算机作为服务器进行拍照，
So, if you want to picture your laptop or
your desktop or your computer as a server,
甚至是手机作为服务器你就会有堆和叠堆
or even a cell phone as a server,
you're gonna have stacks and stacks and
这些都是联网的，这样他们就能高效地处理请求。
stacks of these all networked together so
they can handle requests efficiently.
服务器也特别建立。
And servers are particularly built.
如果你为服务器付钱
If you pay money for a server,
他们建立了一种特殊的方法来保护消费者的硬件
they're built particular ways that
consumer grade hardware is not.
例如，他们可能会纠错内存。
For instance, they're gonna have
probably error correcting memory.
它们的 CPU 速度比一般都快。
They're going to have faster CPUs
than generally are available.
他们会有 40 或 50 个核心 CPU ，对于大多数人来说，
They'll have like 40 or 50 core CPUs
which, for most people, would be complete
因为现代软件不能利用这么多的核心
overkill because modern software doesn't
take advantage of that many cores.
多线程技术很难，完全不同。
It's multi threading is hard,
totally different course.
有多线程的课程吗
Is there a course on multi threading?
我不会教的
I'm not gonna teach that.
这就太艰难了
[LAUGH] That's gonna be way too hard.
但是，为这些情况构建了服务器，并且在您运行应用程序时
But servers are built for these things,
and when you run an application on
一个服务器，它自动地可以派生进程，它可以叉命令，
a server, it automatically can fork
processes, it can fork commands,
它可以在一个线程中处理请求并将其转至另一个线程。
it can handle requests in one thread and
spin off to another one.
但服务器本质上是专门为
But servers, essentially,
are custom built machines specifically for
干扰文件，并不一定与之交互。
disturbing files and
not necessarily interacting with as much.
服务器通常居住在一个称为数据中心的地方。
Servers generally live in
a place called data centers.
数据中心是这些机架和机架以及机架和
Data centers are these racks and
racks and racks and
机架和机架和机架机器通常运行非常冷的环境，
racks and racks and racks machines usually
run really, really cold environments,
就因为电脑运行热，服务器就像感冒一样。
just because computers run hot,
servers like to run cold.
它们通常是干净的，所以不会有很多灰尘。
They're usually clean,
so not a lot of dust.
想象一下如果你有，我不知道，有一万个粉丝在跑吗 ?
Imagine if you have, I don't know,
what is this like, 10,000 fans running?
还有一点灰尘在里面会毁了你的日子
[LAUGH] And a little bit of dust gets
in there, it's gonna ruin your day.
所以他们一般都很干净
So they're generally pretty clean.
他们的安全措施很严密
Security on them is very tight.
想想一家银行，然后把它翻三倍，
Think of a bank, and then triple that, and
这就是数据中心的证券
that's what securities
on data centers are.
因为这是信息，这是权力，这是互联网的运作。
Because this is information, this is
power, this is what the Internet runs on.
例如，几年前， AWS 被关闭了。
For instance,
a couple of years ago AWS went down.
那就是 Amazon Web 服务器，这是世界上最大的主机之一。
So that's Amazon Web Server, that's
one of the biggest hosts in the world.
这就是 Netflix 的用途，很多人使用的东西。
It's what Netflix uses,
what a lot of people use.
其中一个被关闭了，互联网基本被关闭了。
One of them went down and
the Internet went down essentially.
所以我们把网络想象成这样的分布式计算机
So we think of the Internet as these
distributed computers all around
但我们真正依赖的是主要的数据中心
the world, but we really are relying
on main data centers and
不同的路由网络主干
different routing networks, backbones.
就像基础设施的核心部分如果它们下降
There's like core parts of
the infrastructure that if they go down,
我们都被击沉了
we're all sunk.
但我认为最值得注意的是数据中心的有趣之处在于
But I think the most notable thing that
I find interesting about data centers is
他们所消耗的能量是巨大的城市规模巨大
the amount of power they consume
is massive, city scale massive.
它看起来不像这样但是如果你有这么多
It doesn't look like this, but
if you have all these millions and
数以百万计的岩芯在运转它们会吸引大量的能量
millions of cores running,
they're sucking up a lot of power.
你现在看到的是 Facebook，他们建立了自己的数据中心。
And what you'll see now is Facebook,
they've built their own data centers.
谷歌拥有自己的数据中心。
Google has their own data centers.
亚马逊拥有自己的数据中心。
Amazon has their own data centers.
它们都是专门为应用程序构建的专门机器。
And they're all specialized machines
specifically built for their applications.
但他们都做了很多好事
But what a lot of them are doing,
which is good,
他们正在建造这种可再生能源他们正在建造下一个风电场或
is they're building this renewable energy
and they're building next wind farms or
因为它们的能量如此之大
something like that because these eat so
much power.
这完全是数据中心的一个切线。
That's totally a tangent on data centers.
但是，通常，当您收到请求时，它将在某个位置命中数据中心。
But, generally, when you have requests,
it's going to hit a data center somewhere.
有些人喜欢自己的主人
Some people like to host their own.
我们一会儿再谈一下云。
We'll talk a bit more about
the cloud in a second.
但要确定它的样子
But will identify what it looks like.
这是免费开放式源代码映像。
This is the free open source image.
谷歌的人就像很厉害
The ones from Google
are like very impressive.
他们都是大的建筑
They're much larger buildings.
所以一个数据中心就是这个计算机的集合。
So a data center is just this
collection of computers.
通常，它们在不同应用程序，不同公司之间共享。
Often, they're shared between different
applications, different companies.
很多时候，您可以使用 VPS 租用一台服务器或一小部分服务器。
A lot of times you can rent one server or
a fraction of a server with the VPS.
或者，如果您是一家大公司，那么有时您可以拥有整个数据中心。
Or sometimes you can own an entire data
center if you're a big enough company.
>> Jem Young: 让我们来谈谈云。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So
let's talk about the cloud.
数据中心对计算机和
Data centers are newer
thinking about computers and
数据中心实际上是一个相当现代的发明，我说 15 年， 20 年。
data centers are actually fairly modern
invention, I say fairly, say 15, 20 years.
以前想跑个网站什么的，我就有一台电脑的
Before if I wanted to run a website or
host anything, I had a rack of computers
坐在这里如果有人说服务器停机了
sitting here and literally if
someone says the server's down,
我得把它插进去
I had to go plug it back in like that.
这是服务器用来工作的方式。
That was the way servers used to work.
然后人们说，嗯，那是一个 hassle，服务器贵，
Then people said, yeah,
that's a hassle, servers are expensive,
硬件就能过时了
the hardware can get out of date.
如何将服务器关闭而不将所有内容都记下 ?
How do you take a server down
without taking everything down?
所以我们有一个数据中心，所以其他人可以回答
So we have the single data center so
someone else can answer someone
现在的问题是，专门从事硬件工作的人。
else's problem at this point, people that
are specialized in working with hardware.
还有关于云计算的伟大之处
And the great thing about
cloud computing and
数据中心可以位于地球的不同部分。
data centers is they can be in
different parts of the planet.
所以如果我现在在主持这个视频，在我的笔记本电脑上，
So if I were hosting this video right now,
this course on my laptop,
当我去吃午饭或关闭我的电脑时，一切都在下降。
the minute I go to lunch or
close my computer, everything goes down.
这不太好
That's not good.
还有，如果你在说，格陵兰岛，是的，如果你是这样的话，
And also, if you're in say, Greenland,
yeah, if you're in like, say,
格陵兰岛，我不认为它是大规模的。
Greenland, I don't think
it's massive scale.
我现在开始质疑这个标志了
I'm starting to question this logo now,
but
让我们说你在伦敦
let's say you're in London about there.
我们要花很多时间才能到这里
It's gonna take a lot of
hops to get over here.
那为什么没有一个数据中心呢，我不知道，
So why not have a data center in,
I don't know,
非洲要走得更近一点
Africa which is gonna
be a little bit closer.
你不用在大西洋上跳下来
You don't have to make
the hop across the Atlantic.
这会更快一些
It's gonna be a little bit faster.
这就是云的优势
And that's the advantage of the cloud,
就是我可以在世界的不同地方都有同样的应用
is that I can have the same application
running in different parts of the world.
而且它会更快一点
And it's gonna be a little bit faster and
如果你再靠近点你就能减少这方面的差距了
you're gonna reduce that lag
if you're a little bit closer.
还记得我们之前是怎么跑的
Remember how we ran trace route
earlier and it did all those hops.
您通常需要最少的跳数，因为每个中继段都是
You generally want the least number of
hops because every hop is the chance for
有些东西出了问题或者只是速度较慢因为还有纳秒
something to go wrong or it's just slower
because there's still nanoseconds it takes
进行切换以拦截请求并切换到下一个和下一个。
for a switch to intercept a request and
switch to the next one and the next one.
但关于云的伟大之处在于弹性计算的概念。
But the great thing about the cloud
is this idea of elastic computing.
什么是弹性计算?
What is elastic computing?
虽然听起来很像但你可能听到了很多话
It's kind of what it sounds like but,
and you probably hear the phrase a lot,
你都觉得是什么
what do you all think it is?
>> Jem Young: 有人吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Anybody?
>> 扬声器 2: 按需要进行缩放( 如需要 ) 或-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Is it scaling,
like as needed or-
>> Jem Young: 对，对， Sam.
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes, exactly right, Sam.
对就是这样
Yeah, exactly.
听起来就像这样
It's what it sounds like.
它是弹性的
It's, it's elastic.
那真是太好了
What's great about that is and
为什么数据中心在云中很棒是很棒的，我是马克 - 乌尔班斯基。
why data centers are great in the cloud
is great is I am I am Mark Urbanski.
我是大公司的首席执行官 Frontend Masters.com
I am big,
powerful CEO Frontend Masters.com,
我交通很繁忙
and I'm getting a lot of traffic.
这是缩放比例缩放。
It's scaling scaling.
以前我要做的就是买更多的服务器，
In the old days, what I had to do
was I had to buy more servers and
我得买更多的服务器
I had to buy more servers.
但是如果你有一个数据中心我们可以出租，我们就可以说，哎，
But if you have a data center we can
rent out, we can just say like, hey,
我需要再分配三个服务器。
I need to allocate three more servers.
好吧好吧
All right, cool.
按钮
Hit a button.
好了
Done.
我需要缩小范围，因为这是圣诞时间，人们不学习。
I need to scale down because it's
Christmas time and people don't study.
他们不会在圣诞或其他地方做 Fronend Masters 。
They don't do Frontend Masters
over Christmas or something.
我们可以把它放大缩小
We can just scale that back down.
所以我们的成本可以随流量调整而不是定在一定程度上
So our costs can adjust with the traffic
rather than us being fixed with a certain
我们要支付的硬件，维护之类的。
set of hardware that we're paying for,
maintaining and things like that.
你听到了很多弹性云计算的说法，这就是所谓的。
You hear the phrase a lot elastic cloud
computing that's what that's referring to.
例如，真实的生命示例 Netflix，
For instance, real life example, Netflix,
我们每年最忙的一次是圣诞节
one of our busiest times
a year is Christmas.
人们是家庭的家，你知道人们对家庭做什么，
People are home to families and you
know what people do with their families,
他们不想和他们说话
they don't want to talk to them.
他们不会挂的
They don't hang out.
所以他们都在看 Netflix 在他们手机里做什么
So they're all watching Netflix in
their room on their phones doing what
家人都这样
families do.
所以这是我们今年最忙的时候
So, it's one of our busiest
times of the year, so
我们所做的是我们能设定更高的限度
what we do is we can set
the limits much higher.
我们只是放大我们的服务器
We just scale up our servers.
所以我们就放大所有服务器来处理这个额外的流量。
So we just scale up all our servers
to handle this additional traffic.
一旦交通开始下降，我们就把它缩小。
And then once traffic starts to ramp down,
we just scale this back down.
因此，我们不需要支付这些我们不需要的未使用的计算循环。
So we're not paying for this unused
compute cycles that we don't need.
这真的很强大，这在计算世界上是个全新的想法。
That's really powerful and that's a really
new idea in the world of computing.
就像我们需要的那样，在需求能力上。
It's just like this on
demand capacity as we need.
但是老实说大多数人和大多数人都在看这个
But, honestly, most of you,
and most people watching this,
你永远都不需要有服务器的数据中心了
you're never gonna need
a data center with a server.
如果你做得好你会杀了它
If you do, nice job, you are killing it.
如果你需要一个完整的数据中心，但是大多数人，
You're doing really great if you need
an entire data center, but most people,
我们只需要一小部分服务器
we just need a tiny little
fraction of one server.
因为记得我说的服务器有五六十个内核，
Because remember how I said
servers have 50, 60 hundred cores,
其实不知道是什么限制，大概是挺高的，
actually don't know what the limit is,
probably pretty high,
可能在超级计算机上成千上万的人
probably in the thousands for
you at the supercomputers.
有人知道吗
Anybody know?
这不重要
It's not important.
但我们需要的是，我们只需要一小部分的服务器。
But what we need is we just probably need
a fraction of a fraction of a server.
我们今天要创建的服务器在一台服务器上是一个核心
And the server we're gonna create today
is gonna be one core on one server,
就像是一小部分服务器的一小部分
which is just like a fraction of
a fraction of a fraction of a server.
因为这就是我们所需要的，为什么我们不需要付出代价呢 ?
Because that's all we need, and
why pay for things we don't need?
这就是云计算背后的理念
And that's the idea behind cloud
computing in this capacity,
你只需要付出代价
you just pay for what you need.
我们要做的是做一个服务器，把它切成小块，
So what we do is we take a server,
we just slice it into little chunks and
这些组块无法相互交流
these chunks can't talk to each other.
有一个过程隔离的想法
There's this idea of process isolation,
这就是你在运营我的网站 party.com
which is you're running
I like to party.com.
不知道请不要去
Don't know please don't go there.
我不知道该网站是什么样的，我不承担这个责任。
I don't know what that website is like,
I take no responsibility for that.
但我想运行 Jovian.com 我们可以在同一台服务器上运行
But I wanna run Jovian.com,
we can run on the same server and
我们甚至都不知道那是什么
we don't even know that either,
and we just ran what we need.
这是一个非常有力的想法，我认为是完全低估的。
And that's a really powerful idea
that I think is totally underrated.